(
"ai_sub_version": "2.5.0",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 2,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 12,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"web_search_tool": "duckduckgo",
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": "libx264"
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
君の心の中を全部見せてよ
Show me everything inside your heart
何が好きで何が嫌いで
What you like and what you hate
僕をどのくらいかな
And how much do you like me?
今日はどんな服着て
What kind of clothes are you wearing today
どこで何をしてるの
Where and what are you doing?
全部全部　隠さないでいいよ
You don't have to hide anything at all
僕に教えて
Just tell me
経験なんて気にしない
I don't care about things like experience
偏見バカバカしくない
Prejudices are just ridiculous
汚さないで　そばにおかえり
Don't let it get dirty, come back to my side
1人で泣きゃいい
If only I could just cry alone...
でも一人は笑えない
But I can't smile alone.
ずっと欲しかった言葉も
Even the words I've always wanted...
しらふのままじゃ出てこないなら
If they won't come out while I'm sober...
3つ数えて
I'll count to three.
世界が止まればいいのに
If only the world would stop...
あぁ 戻れない
Ah, I can't go back.
触れて溶け合うくらいの距離で
At a distance where we touch and melt together,
僕のことだけ見ててよ
please look only at me.
跡付けてよ 消えないくらいに
Leave a mark so deep it won't disappear.
ほらね 今 ギュッとして
Look, now, hold me tight.
曖昧だっていいよなんて
Saying things like "Ambiguity is fine"...
僕は分かるから
I can see right through it.
気付かないふりしてあげるって
I'll pretend not to notice,
だからね 今 スキって言ってよ
so please, say you like me right now.
スキって言ってよ
Say you like me.
永遠なんてありゃしない
There's no such thing as eternity.
現然なんて嘘ばかり
Reality is nothing but lies.
期待したいなんて傲ばかり
Desiring to hope is just arrogance.
顔色伺うもうギリギリ
Checking your expression, I'm at my limit.
1人で泣きゃいい
If only I could just cry alone...
でも1人は笑えない
But I can't smile alone.
ずっと欲しかった言葉も
Even the words I've always wanted...
思ってるままじゃ出てこないなら
If they won't come out as I feel them...
3つ数えて
I'll count to three.
世界が変わればいいのに
If only the world would change...
あぁ 戻れない
Ah, I can't go back.
ガラガラと音立てて崩れる
Collapsing with a clatter,
景色の中を落ちていく
falling through the scenery.
見つけ出してよ 離れないくらいに
Find me, so we'll never be apart.
ほらね 今 ギュッとして
Look, now, hold me tight.
何回だっていいよなんて
Saying things like "Any number of times is fine"...
僕は分かるから
I can see right through it.
いつか最後に聞かせてくれるって
That you'll let me hear it one last time.
だからね また スキって言ってよ
So please, say you like me again.
夜が明けるまで話を聞いて
Listen to my story until the night breaks.
終わらない夢みたいに輝いて見えた
It looked as if it were shining like an endless dream.
どうか今だけ消さないで
Please, just for now, don't let it fade away.
冗談じゃないよ
I'm not joking.
君のいない明日なんて全部いらない
I don't need a tomorrow without you.
ずっと一緒だよね
We'll be together forever, right?
触れて溶け合うくらいの距離で
At a distance where we touch and melt together,
僕のことだけ見ててよ
please look only at me.
跡付けてよ 消えないくらいに
Leave a mark so deep it won't disappear.
ほらね 今 ギュッとして
Look, now, hold me tight.
何回だっていいよなんて
Saying things like "Any number of times is fine"...
僕は分かるから
I can see right through it.
気付かないふりしてあげるって
I'll pretend not to notice,
だからね 今 スキって言ってよ
so please, say you like me right now.
スキって言ってよ
Say you like me.
ないない
Nai Nai (None/Not there)
灰のない
No ash,
深いかげばかり
only deep shadows.
アイのない
No love,
個体 人形(doll)みたい
an individual like a doll.
自分不在
Self absent,
どこにもいない
nowhere to be found.
ないじゃない？
Isn't that right?
曖昧なアイ
Ambiguous love,
色の無い眼(eye)
colorless eyes.
擬態 意外!
Mimicry, unexpected!
他人事みたい
Like someone else's business.
おかげさまで
Thanks to you,
どちらさま？
who are you?
お互いさまさま
We're both in the same boat.
何者でもないまま
Remaining as a nobody,
何もできないまま
unable to do anything.
生きるのは無駄ですが
Living is futile, but...
悪いことですか？
is that a bad thing?
ここにいない いない いないのは
The one who isn't here, isn't here...
自分 自分
is me, myself.
誰も見ない 見ない 見ないまま
Without anyone looking, looking...
吐き捨てて さようなら
I spit it out and say goodbye.
嬉しくない 悲しくもない
I'm not happy, nor am I sad.
透明な気分
A transparent feeling.
足りない自分 合わす顔もない
My lacking self has no face to show.
ない
None.
笑えないじゃない
I can't even smile, can I?
ない
None.
見ないまま
Without even looking...
吐き捨ててさようなら
spit it out and say goodbye.
形も失くして
Even my form is lost
いっそなくしてしまえばいい
If I throw it away, it'll be fine
またひとつ
Again, one by one
ひとつから始めればいい
Starting from the beginning, it'll be fine
ここにいない、ここにいない
I'm not here, I'm not here
ここにいない
I'm not here
のは自分、自分
It's me, me
誰も見ない
No one looks,
見ない
looks,
見ないまま
looking at me in this state
吐き捨ててさようなら
Discarded, bye-bye
嬉しいくらい悲しくもない
Happy or sad, it doesn't matter
透明な気分
Transparent mood
足りない自分 合わす顔もない
I don't have enough, I don't have a face to match
（ない）ない（ない）ない
(Not) not (not) not
ここにいない、ここにいない
I'm not here, I'm not here
ここにいない
I'm not here
のは自分、自分
It's me, me
誰も見ない
No one looks,
見ない
looks,
見ないまま
looking at me in this state
吐き捨ててさようなら
Discarded, bye-bye
はい！というわけで聴いてくれてありがとう！
Yes! So thank you for listening!
改めて！
Once again!
ハローボ！ホロライブ所属0期生、
Hello-bo! Hololive's 0th gen,
バーチャル高性能ロボットのロボ子こと、
the virtual high-performance robot Roboco,
ロボ子だよー！
it's Roboco!
今日は僕の誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to my birthday live today!
えー、もう高性能ハテナみたいなコメント拾わないからね？
Um, I won't pick up comments like "high performance?" anymore, okay?
だってもう今日9歳！主役！
Because I'm already 9 years old today! I'm the star!
あ、やべ。もう誕生日のこと質問しようと思ったのに言っちゃった。
Ah, oops. I was going to ask about my birthday, but I already said it.
はい、そう。ロボ子なんと今年で9歳になりました！
Yes, that's right. Roboco has turned 9 years old this year!
9歳！
9 years old!
やばくない？来年もう二桁になる。
Isn't it crazy? Next year I'll be in the double digits.
やばい、やばすぎる。
Crazy, too crazy.
ワクワクしてきた。最後の一桁楽しんでいきたいと思います！
I'm getting excited. I want to enjoy the last single digit!
はい、というわけで、本日のハッシュタグを紹介します！
Alright, so I'll introduce today's hashtag!
ドジャン！本日のハッシュタグは...
Ta-da! Today's hashtag is...
あ、こっちだった。
Oh, it was this way.
＃ロボ子爆誕2025ですね。
It's #RobocoBirthday2025.
皆さん見えましたか？
Did you see it, everyone?
きっと高性能な君たちだったら、
I'm sure if it's you high-performance people,
もう＃ロボ子爆誕2025つけて呟いていることでしょう！
you're already tweeting with #RobocoBirthday2025!
はい、たくさん僕の可愛いスクショと共に
Yes, please post them
ポストしてってくださいね！
with many of my cute screenshots!
こうして人は循環していくんですよ。ポスト！
This is how people circulate. Post!
はい、というわけで、まずは今日はね、僕のオリジナル曲「With Love」から始まって
Alright, so first for today, I started with my original song "With Love"
「ないない」を歌ったんですけど。
and then sang "Nai Nai".
どうでしたか？
How was it?
「With Love」、「With Love」はMVと同じね、ウルフカットじゃなくて、
For "With Love", same as the MV, not the wolf cut,
通常の強そうなロングのやつで巻き巻きでいったんですけど。
but I went with the usual strong-looking long hair with curls.
え、どうだった？良かった？
Um, how was it? Was it good?
そう、なんかもう久々だよね。
Yeah, it's been a while, right?
このナイティドレスとかも。
For this nighty dress too.
ウルフカットなんて初めてなんじゃない？
Is it maybe the first time for the wolf cut?
ショートカット。
The short hair.
ショート動画でしか撮らないからね。
Because I only take shots for short videos.
そう、セクシーでしょ？
Yeah, sexy, right?
そして、ステージがなんかすごいかっこいい！
And the stage is somehow really cool!
え、かっこよすぎる！
Eh, it's too cool!
ふー、今回はこんな感じなんですね。
Phew, so it's like this this time.
今日はなんか色々楽しみなことがいっぱいありそうだけど。
It seems like there are lots of things to look forward to today.
え、一体何で今日このステージなんだろうな？
Eh, I wonder why this stage today?
なんと後でね、
And then later...
うわさがいるらしいんですけれども
There seems to be a rumor...
コメントにいないロボさがいるらしくてですね
Apparently, there's a Robo-sa who isn't in the comments.
気になった方は探してみてくださいね
If you're curious, please try to find them.
いるかな？
Are they here?
あれ？ロボさいるかなー？
Wait? Is Robo-sa here?
あれ？いるかなー？
Wait? Are they here?
きっと見つけてる奴多い...
I'm sure many of you have found them...
あ！正解！正解！ここにいます！
Ah! Correct! Correct! They're right here!
特等席！
The best seat!
お前はいったい誰なんだー！
Who on earth are you?!
ずっと僕のことリハ中も見守っててくれてます
They've been watching over me since the rehearsal.
ロボさ可愛ちいね
Robo-sa is so cute.
はい、というわけで今日は誕生日のためにいっぱい、いっぱい
Anyway, for my birthday today, I've prepared...
みんな、そして僕が楽しめる歌をたくさんね、ご用意いたしましたので
...lots and lots of songs that everyone and I can enjoy,
いっぱいレッスンもしたので、楽しんでってください！
so please enjoy, as I've practiced a lot!
はい、この後は、そろそろ一人でも歌うと思うんだけど
Okay, after this, I'll probably sing solo soon,
ゲストも呼んでって歌っちゃおうかなと思います
...but I'm also thinking of calling guests and singing together.
最初は誰だろうな？
I wonder who's first?
んーなんか、すっごいキスいっぱいしたい気分になってきた
Hmm, somehow I feel like giving lots of kisses.
なんでだろう... チュチュチュ...
I wonder why... *mwah mwah mwah*...
ようこそお越しなさったご主人様
Welcome, Master
隣に座って せーの
Sit next to me, and ready...
萌 萌 萌 萌
Moe, moe, moe, moe
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who would be happy with this?
ねえ教えて 笑顔でアップップ
Hey, tell me, with a funny face
愛想を忘れて ご苦労様
Forget the pleasantries, thanks for your hard work
私とあなたで せーの
With you and me, ready...
Luv, luv, luv, luv
こんなんで誰が喜ぶのさ
Who would be happy with this?
ねえ教えて 笑顔でアップップ
Hey, tell me, with a funny face
ひらりはらり 女の子
Fluttering, fluttering, a girl
ふわりふわり 言葉の嘘
Softly, softly, the lies in words
それってつまり 収めな、子 感情的リアル 笑顔でアップップ
In other words, settle it, child; emotional reality, with a funny face
人は見かけによらぬもの
People aren't what they seem
嘘を嘘だと見抜けばいい
You just need to see through the lies
知取ったかな 袖裾の香
Did you notice the scent on my sleeve?
あっぱりはら さっぱりはら アン・ドゥ・トロワ
Appari hara sappari hara, un deux trois
間違ったご指名をいただきます
I'll take your mistaken nomination
私とあなたで せーの
With you and me, ready...
ダ ダ ダ ダ
Da da da da
これは派手にご苦労様
This is flashy, thanks for your hard work
遊びましょう 笑顔でアップップ
Let's play, with a funny face
ひらりはらり ここはどこ
Fluttering, fluttering, where am I?
ふわりふわり 外へ見せよう
Softly, softly, let's show it to the world
それってつまり 収めな、子 感情的リアル 笑顔でアップップ
In other words, settle it, child; emotional reality, with a funny face
奪い出す 秘密の金
Steal away the secret gold
終わることのないこの世界
In this never-ending world
哀しい子供は
Sad children...
空しい子供は
...empty children,
眠らせて
let them sleep.
あーままごと 遊びましょう 笑顔でアップップ
Ah, playing house, let's play with a funny face
ひらりはらり 女の子
Fluttering, fluttering, a girl
ふわりふわり 言葉の嘘
Softly, softly, the lies in words
それってつまり 収めな、子 感情的リアル 笑顔でアップップ
In other words, settle it, child; emotional reality, with a funny face
遊びましょう 笑顔でアップップ
Let's play, with a funny face
アップップ
Funny face
あれが正解なんて
That that's the correct answer...
誰の成れの果て？
...is whose shadow of their former self?
（なんだっての悶々々...）
(What the hell? It's so frustrating...)
答えも欲しいのも 一個てこれだけ
The only answer I want is this one.
悩んだってしょうがないじゃんね
There's no point in worrying about it, right?
あれは夢だったって思うことにしたって（つら）
Even if I decide to think it was all a dream (it hurts)...
で... 全然思わないけど
But... I don't feel that way at all.
Help me, follower
Just fighting
若さに負け
Losing to the young
Next, next
Lucky lucky and lucky!
アリヨ
A-li-a
割り切れたらさ
If I could just make sense of it...
パレード
Parade
割り切れたらさ
If only I could just split it up
パレード
Parade
楽なのにとか
Even though it would be easier
もうやだ
I'm done
万獣新生界か
A new world of ten thousand beasts?
安泰以外は
Anything but peace
安泰以外は いらない ない ない
Anything but peace, I don't need it, no, no, no
払いで終わりや
End it with an exorcism
あるはずのない何か
Something that shouldn't exist
あったならば ハッピージャンピーヤ
If it did, it'd be happy jumpy, yeah
あんたのその程度
That's all you've got?
知るこのテリトリー
I know this territory
繋いだら無理 一生離さないわ
Once connected, it's impossible, I'll never let go
あんたのその手札
That hand of yours
知るこのテリトリー
I know this territory
掴んだら 最後 見知りおきを my love
Once I've grabbed it, it's the end, remember me, my love
My love
これで終わりなんて
To think it ends here
I got it my mindなんて
Thinking I've got it in my mind
どうにかこうにかやって
Doing this and that
願って 願ってね
Wishing, wishing
エスケープしたいし 衝動
I want to escape, and the urge...
なも我慢 定期ペンペンペン
Nothing but patience, a regular pen-pen-pen
痛い言えば毎日 舞うていけるけど
If I say it hurts every day, I can still dance, but
ダブルペナンスなんて関係ない
Double penance doesn't matter
慣れよりも根拠
Base it on proof rather than habit
必要ないもう結構
I don't need it, I've had enough
足は足だ 見といてよレイディ
A foot is a foot, watch me, lady
もう今日で終わらせたいなって
Thinking I want to end it today
リスタートできたらって
Wishing I could restart
でも無理 もう
But I can't, already
What's your problem?
パレード
Parade
割り切れたらさ
If only I could divide it up
サヨナラ
Farewell
楽なのにとか
Even though it would be easier
もうやだ
I'm done
万獣新生界か
A new world of ten thousand beasts?
安泰以外は
Anything but peace
安泰以外は いらない ない ない
Anything but peace, I don't need it, no, no, no
払いで終わりや
End it with an exorcism
あるはずのない何か
Something that shouldn't exist
あったならば ハッピージャンピーヤ
If it did, it'd be happy jumpy, yeah
あんたのその程度
That's all you've got?
知るこのテリトリー
I know this territory
繋いだら無理 一生離さないわ
Once connected, it's impossible, I'll never let go
あんたのその手札
That hand of yours
知るこのテリトリー
I know this territory
掴んだら 最後 見知りおきを my love
Once I've grabbed it, it's the end, remember me, my love
My love
見知りおきを my love
Remember me, my love
半端なら K.O.
Half-assed? It's a K.O.
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
If you wanna float, go ahead
開演準備しちゃおうか
Why don't we start preppin' for the opening?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Cry or laugh, just love me, okay?
ほら say no
C'mon, "Say No"
低音響かせろ
Bring the bass
なんだかな...ってつまんないこともあるでしょう
Things tend to get boring, don't they?
ロンリー論理のノート
The notebook of lonely logic
ハンディー本気脱走
The handy, serious escape
やんなっちゃって泥に bad
Got sick of it and mud, bad
ご法度だろうが溺れて堕ちて
It's forbidden, but I'm drowning, falling
さあさあ いっそもっとがんばって
Now then, just work even harder
踊るまでもっとがんばって
Keep at it until you dance
常套句も 一人より二人
Even the clichés, better with two than one
増えたら安心 心配ないや
When there's more, it's reassuring, no need to worry
オーライ 任せてドンマイ
Alright, leave it to me, don't mind
縁なんて 皆で乗っかっちゃえば
With our ties, if we all just hop on
案外サクッと いっちゃいそう
We might just get there quite easily
半端なら K.O.
Half-assed? It's a K.O.
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
If you wanna float, go ahead
開演準備しちゃおうか
Why don't we start preppin' for the opening?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Cry or laugh, just love me, okay?
ほら say no
C'mon, "Say No"
低音響かせろ
Bring the bass
今宵はアンダーバリュー
Tonight is an undervalue
踊りだせ 踊りだせ
Start dancing, start dancing
孤独さえも 舞い踊れ
Even loneliness, dance along
痛みまで お幸せ
Even the pain, be happy
ここらでバイバイ レッツゴー
Let's say goodbye here, let's go
怒鳴れど 惑えど 即興の化粧盤
Even if you yell or get confused, on this makeshift stage
抑え込んで 突っ込んで しまっちゃうでしょう
You'll probably just suppress it, dive in, and stow it away
アッパーなテンション
High tension
迷い込んじゃって のっそり
Getting lost and sluggishly
ドバっと吹き出すのは
What's gushing out
本音の独り言
Is my true inner monologue
別に興味ない 他に関係ない
I'm not interested, it doesn't matter
塞ぎ込んで 絶好調
Feeling down and in top form
合図を奏でて ぱら ぱら ぱら ぱら いぇい
Playing the signal, para para para para yay
ほら 集まって 夜行だ
C'mon, gather 'round, it's a night parade
泣いていこうか
Let's go crying
よう うな垂れてるその兄ちゃん
Yo, that guy with his head hanging low
何か辛い事あったんか？
Did something bad happen?
俺で良けりゃ話してくんない？
If you're cool with me, wanna talk about it?
力になるぜ
Maybe I can be of help
一体どんなことがあった？
What in the world happened?
そりゃ酷え話だ兄弟
That sounds rough, brother
これをやるから元気出しな
Here, take this, and cheer up
金ならまた今度でいいさ
Money can wait until next time
Shanti Shanti Shanti Shanti
Shanti Happy Candy
Happy Happy Happy Candy
Many Many Money
眠らない夜のチャイナタウン
Even the sleepless nights in Chinatown...
その全てが縄張り
...are your turf
老若男女問わずお客
Regardless of age or gender, you treat your guests
使い終わったら捨てりゃいい
And once you're done, you can throw them away
今夜も来たのかい
Did you come again tonight?
お気に召したかい
Did you like it?
代金はこれくらい
How much will it cost?
え？払えないのかい？
Eh? Can't you pay?
ならばしょうがない
Well, it can't be helped
君にぴったりの仕事があるから
Since you're the one that fits the job
こっちについてきな
Follow me
(こっちについてきな)
(Follow me...)
汚れて酒場が剥がれた女
A woman whose bar's peeled and soiled
嗄れた甲板掲げた女
A woman who raised a hoarse deck
高々舞い触れ逸れた幼女
A little girl who strayed from the high dance
端からあいつの思惑通りだ
It's all according to his plan from the start
気狂ってる目散歩中
With crazy eyes, walking around
血売ってもい納得
Satisfied even after selling blood
超神道リンドウ咲かせた果て
Gentian bloomed at Super Shinto's end
盲信の心お抱え給え
Hold onto your blind faith
黙れ 座れ 黙れや
Shut up, sit down, shut the hell up
殴れ 殴れ 殴れや
Punch, punch, punch 'em out
縛れ 縛れ 縛れや
Tie up, tie up, tie 'em down
バラせ バラせ バラせや
Dismantle, dismantle, tear 'em apart
今夜はどうだい
How is it tonight?
お気に召したかい
Did you like it?
代金はこれくらい
How much will it cost?
生きてりゃお客
If you're alive, you're a guest
死んでりゃ商材
If you're dead, you're merchandise
そつなくむだなくころがしてビジネス
Rolling them efficiently, just business
どっちを向いてんだ
Which way are you looking?
はーい！というわけで
Haaai! So...
かっこいいでしょ？
Cool, right?
はい、こちらがロボ子の新衣装となります！
Yes, this is Roboco's new outfit!
見て下から。超かっこいいの。ドヤ。
Look from below. It's super cool. *smug*
え、サングラス似合いすぎでは？
Wait, don't the sunglasses suit me too well?
やばい、みんなが恋しちゃう。
Oh no, everyone's going to fall in love.
俺に惚れると、火傷するぜ？
If you fall for me, you'll get burned.
やべー、草すぎる。
Man, that's too funny.
笑わないでね、わらわらやめてね。
Don't laugh, stop with the 'lol's.
はい、というわけで、見てこれ、かっこいいでしょ。
Alright, so look at this, cool right?
なんかさ、指についてんだけど。まだよく見えないね。
Like, there's something on my finger. You can't see it well yet.
え、踊る時に、カラーライン衣装からチェンジしたんだけど、
I changed from the color-line outfit while dancing,
チェンジした瞬間、ちゃんとみんな分かった？
but did everyone notice the moment I changed?
待っててくれました？一瞬だったでしょう？
Did you wait for me? It was just a split second, wasn't it?
嬉しい。可愛い、かっこいい。ね、これなんか両方あるよね。
I'm so happy. It's cute and cool. Right? It's kind of both.
かっこいいし可愛いよね。プリティーでクールなの、これ。
It's cool and cute. It's 'pretty and cool'.
いっぱい見て、いっぱい見て。足からちょっと見てく？
Take a good look, take a good look. Shall we start from the feet?
おー見てーえーやばい。かっこよすぎるんだが。
Oh, look... Whoa, this is crazy. It's just too cool.
見て、これロボット特有のさ、この…人間だったら多分めっちゃ歩きづらいんじゃ？
Look, this is something unique to robots... If I were human, it would probably be really hard to walk in?
みんな多分歩けないよね、この靴。僕歩けるんだけどさ。
No one else could probably walk in these shoes. But I can.
おーこの靴で多分僕走ったら多分めっちゃ倍こけると思うから、
Oh, if I tried to run in these, I'd probably fall twice as much, so...
歩きます。どう？どう？どう？
I'll just walk. How is it? How is it? How is it?
はい、そして上からね。かっこよく決まって、
Yes, and from the top. Looking cool and sharp—
ベルトあればあるだけいいですからね。いっぱい付けてもらえました。
you can never have too many belts, right? I had a lot of them added.
今回マジで装飾品もかっこいい。キラキラ。
The accessories are really cool this time too. So sparkly.
金色のネックレス。これダイヤとか雷が付いてるのかな？うん。
A gold necklace. I wonder if these are diamonds or lightning bolts? Yeah.
あとなんか姿がちょっとおかしくなってるけど。
Also, my form is a bit strange right now, but...
僕の新衣装に合わせてロボさがイヤリングにいたり。
Robo-sa is even in my earrings to match my new outfit.
新しい丸眼鏡はちょっとクールで装飾品もいっぱい付いてるし。
The new round glasses are pretty cool with lots of details.
何よりこのでっかいお団子かわっちでしょう？
And above all, these big buns are so cute, right?
もふもふもふもふ。
Fluffy, fluffy, fluffy, fluffy.
僕毛量多いの大好き。
I love having lots of hair volume.
ね、このもふもふ可愛いよね。これ脱げるのかって？えー？
Right, this fluff is cute, isn't it? 'Can I take it off?' Eh?
だって指だってまだちゃんと見れてないもんね。
But you haven't even seen my fingers properly yet.
脱げちゃうのかな？あとで。
I wonder if it'll come off? Later.
あとでお楽しみにしていください。はい、というわけで…
Please look forward to it later. Yes, and so...
でもライブ以来だよ、Colorize衣装来たの。
But it's been since the live since I wore the Colorize outfit.
かっこよかったでしょう？ギャル。ね。
It was cool, right? Totally 'gal'. Right.
めちゃめちゃ映えてたよね。うん。燃えんチャコファイヤーもね。
It looked really great on screen. Yeah. 'Moen Chako Fire' too.
もう早くエリザベスが3Dモデル出ること僕待ってるから。ピース！
I'm already waiting for Elizabeth to get a 3D model. Peace!
でも一緒に歌えてすごく楽しかった。
But it was so much fun to sing together.
ありがとねみんな。
Thank you, everyone.
はい、そして『フォニイ』と『シャンティ』とソロも歌いましたけれども。
Yes, and I also sang 'Phony', 'Shanti', and a solo.
爆上げ、かっこすぎロボ子さん。うん。
It was hyped up—Roboko is just too cool. Yeah.
低音層いますからね。
I've got that low register, after all.
ロボ子の低音が大好きすぎる民たち。うん。いつもありがと。
To my fans who love Roboko's low voice... Yeah. Thanks as always.
すごく嬉しい。僕も気持ちよく歌いました。
I'm so happy. I felt great singing too.
あ、ところでステージがなんか進化して
Oh, by the way, did you notice the stage evolved
ドラゴンくんが生まれてたの気づきました？こいつどこから来たんやお前ね。
and a Dragon-kun was born? Where on earth did you come from, you?
ロボさん食われちゃいそうだよね。うん。一回ロボさんをドラゴンの口の中に入れてみようかな？
Looks like Robo-sa is about to be eaten. Yeah. I wondered if I should try putting Robo-sa in the dragon's mouth?
ちょっと悩んだ。
I thought about it for a bit.
でも入れなかった。僕えらい！
But I didn't. I'm such a good girl!
うわ、あいつの上に乗下りすぎるだろう。うん。
Whoa, I want to ride on top of him so badly. Yeah.
というわけでですね。
So, anyway...
もう次の歌も歌いたいんですけれども。
I want to sing the next song soon.
せっかくこの衣装なので。
Especially since I'm in this outfit.
なんかゲストの中にめちゃチャイナしやーる奴がいるらしいんですよ。
I heard there's someone very 'China-esque' among the guests.
歌っちゃおうかな？
Shall we sing?
ね、ドラゴンくん？歌いたいよね？ね？
Right, Dragon-kun? You want to sing, don't you? Right?
「あー、歌いたい！」って言ってる気がするんで。
'Ah, I want to sing!' I feel like that's what he's saying.
じゃあ、早速呼んでいきましょう！
So, let's call her out right away!
す、す、すいちゃーん！
Sui-, Sui-, Suichan!
ロボ子ー久しぶりー！お誕生日おめでとう！
Roboko, long time no see! Happy Birthday!
すいちゃんありがとー！ね、見て見て、新衣装！
Suichan, thank you! Hey, look, look! My new outfit!
めっちゃ可愛い！めっちゃ可愛い！
It's so cute! It's so cute!
一緒に『いーあるふぁんくらぶ』歌おう！
Let's sing 'I-Aru Fanclub' together!
いいよ！
You got it!
神戸 中央区 元町駅前
In Kobe, Chuo ward, Motomachi station front
今日から ドキドキ ニーハオ講習会
Starting today, a heart-pounding Nihao workshop
大人 中高生 おばあちゃんに
To adults, middle and high schoolers, and grandmas,
「こんにちは」
Hello!
ダメダメ ここでは あなたも ニーハオ
No, no—everyone here says 'Nihao' too!
ニーハオ！
Nihao!
マジでテキスト三ページ
Seriously, three pages into the textbook,
早くも…
Already...
そこはとにかく一生懸命やるぞ
I'll just do my very best there!
一万三千の月謝は安くない
13,000 yen for lessons isn't cheap.
好好大家 ご機嫌いかが
Hello everyone, how are you doing?
お母さん お馬さん
Mother, horse,
（お母さん お馬さん）
(Mother, horse)
ここはどこ 君は誰
Where is this? Who are you?
（ここはどこ 君は誰）
(Where is this? Who are you?)
大好きなワン・リーホンに
To my favorite Wang Leehom...
大好きだって言うため
To say 'I love you'...
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地
High, high, China, a bit of a dreamlike state,
いーあるふぁんくらぶ
1-2 Fan Club!
だんだん君と同じ言葉が使えるね
Bit by bit, I can use the same words as you.
うぉーあいにー 言えるかな
'Wǒ ài nǐ,' I wonder if I can say it?
ねえ見て リュウちゃん
Hey, look, Ryu-chan!
リュウちゃん リュウ...
Ryu-chan... Ryu...
そこで知り合った女子高生 ミカちゃん
I met a high school girl there, Mika-chan.
曰く台湾でジェイ・チョウ의コンサート
She says Jay Chou is in concert in Taiwan.
それは行かなきゃだめだ ところで
I've got to go! By the way...
ミカちゃん知れっと言ってるけど 海外だよ
Mika-chan, you say it so casually, but it's abroad!
マジでエンジンかかってんな ミカちゃん
You're really revving your engine, Mika-chan!
そこはとにかく便乗して頑張るか
For now, let's jump on the bandwagon and do our best.
六万数千の旅費も 安くない
60,000-plus in travel expenses isn't cheap.
それでは再見 バイト探さなきゃ
Then goodbye! I've got to find a part-time job.
すみません お嬢さん
Excuse me, young lady,
（小籠包一個いくらでしょう）
(How much is one soup dumpling?)
小籠包一個いくらでしょう
How much is one soup dumpling?
（小籠包一個いくらでしょう）
(How much is one soup dumpling?)
天国のレスリー・チャンに
To Leslie Cheung in heaven...
おやすみなさいって言うため
To say 'goodnight'...
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地
High, high, China, a bit of a dreamlike state,
いーあるふぁんくらぶ
1-2 Fan Club!
だんだん君の伝えたい気持ちがわかってく
Gradually, I'm understanding the feelings you want to convey.
憧れて 夢中になって
Admiring you, getting obsessed...
一ヶ月 二ヶ月 半年過ぎた
One month, two months, half a year has passed.
リア友は 少し減ったけど
My real-life friends have decreased a bit, but...
それも仕方ないや
I guess that can't be helped.
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地
High, high, China, a bit of a dreamlike state,
いーあるふぁんくらぶ
1-2 Fan Club!
だんだん君と同じ言葉が使えるね
Bit by bit, I can use the same words as you.
ハイハイチャイナ ちょちょ夢心地
High, high, China, a bit of a dreamlike state,
いーあるふぁんくらぶ
1-2 Fan Club!
だんだん君の伝えたい気持ちがわかってく
Gradually, I'm understanding the feelings you want to convey.
うぉーあいにー 言わせてよ
'Wǒ ài nǐ,' let me say it.
いーあるふぁんくらぶ
1-2 Fan Club!
うぉーあいにー 言えるかな
'Wǒ ài nǐ,' I wonder if I can say it?
うぉーあいにー
'Wǒ ài nǐ.'
大家、謝謝！
Everyone, thank you!
おー、びっくりした！ありがとう！
Whoa, you surprised me! Thank you!
ミニボタンやめてね
Stop hitting the mini button!
大家、謝謝！
Everyone, thank you!
ありがとう、ありがとう、ありがとう
Thank you, thank you, thank you!
素敵
Lovely.
え、素敵じゃない、あなた？
Wait, aren't you lovely?
どこが素敵？
What's lovely?
もちろん
Of course...
太もも
The thighs.
ねえ、全部そこじゃないの！
Hey, it's not all about that!
もちろん
Of course...
太ももフェチなんだもん
I'm a thigh fetishist, after all.
太もも、好き
I like thighs.
どこら辺太もも？
Where about the thighs?
え、エッチだから
Well, because they're erotic.
ねえ！
Hey!
僕大好き、そういうの。ちょっと露出してるの、ちょっとだけ
I love that kind of thing. The slight exposure, just a bit.
素敵じゃないですか
Isn't it lovely?
いいよね
It's good, isn't it?
でもあなたもね
But you too.
あ、僕ここ好き
Oh, I like this part.
この、ここ！
This, right here!
お揃いです
It's a matching look.
ここフェチ。フェチズム
A fetish for this part. Fetishism...
あ、たまんねー
Oh, it's irresistible.
たまんねー
Irresistible.
最高だ
It's the best.
人のこと言えない
Look who's talking.
もうお互いそういう絡みしかできない
Now we can only interact like this.
やばい
This is bad.
長年の適当な絡みになっちまってよ
It's become years of casual banter.
適当な緑仙です
I'm the casual Ryushen.
はい、緑仙が来てくれました！
Yes, Ryushen has come to join us!
ばんぱいー！
Banpai!
ぴったりでしょ、今回
Perfect, isn't it, this time?
ね
Right.
もう呼びたくて呼びたくて仕方なかった
I wanted to invite you over so badly.
嬉しい
I'm happy.
何ここっぽいポーズとか？
What, like a pose that fits the theme?
歌えたのがね、まず嬉しいよ
First of all, I'm happy we could sing together.
え、そうだよね。確かに、歌ったことないね
Yeah, that's true. Certainly, we've never sung together before.
そうなんですよ。歌ったことなかったから
That's right. Because we'd never sung it before.
何これ？
What is this?
わかんない
I don't know.
なんか喋りながらポーズしておこうかなと思って
I thought I'd strike some poses while talking.
待て。待て。待て
Wait. Wait. Wait.
みんな落ち着け。落ち着いて
Everyone, calm down. Calm down.
写真は撮っていい、勝手に
You can take photos, go ahead.
いい感じで撮っていい？
Can I take some good shots?
おう。勝手にスクショを撮って、
Yeah. Take screenshots as you like,
タグをつけて投稿してほしい
and I want you to post them with the tag.
ハッシュタグは何ですか？
What is the hashtag?
ハッシュタグは、
The hashtag is...
そんなことはここを見ればわかるだろ！
You can tell just by looking here!
はしょらないでよ！
Don't cut it short!
えー、長年だと手抜くんですか？
Eh, do you cut corners after all these years?
そんなことないです
That's not it at all.
何ですか、途中の...
What was that in the middle...
ん？
Hmm?
途中の...
In the middle...
あ、裏指した、あなた
Oh, you pointed with the back of your finger.
ん？だって、あなたの名前って緑仙じゃないですか
Hmm? Because your name is Ryushen, isn't it?
緑仙ですよ
I'm Ryushen.
龍！
Dragon!
あ、龍。あ、龍。龍、龍、龍、龍！
Ah, a dragon. A dragon. Dragon, dragon!
ほらほら、龍ちゃん。
Look, look, it's Ryu-chan.
「痛ー」ってなっちゃう。
That's gonna make me say 'Ouch'.
だってだって、あそこ僕に任されたんだもん。
Because, because, I was entrusted with that part.
しかもさ、僕のこと「龍ちゃん」って呼んでるよね、今日。
And besides, you're calling me 'Ryu-chan' today, aren't you?
龍ちゃん、今日だけ。
Ryu-chan, just for today.
でも普段は「翠」とか言うんですよね。
But usually you call me 'Midori' or something.
今日だけ「龍ちゃん」とか言って。
Saying 'Ryu-chan' just for today...
龍ちゃん！
Ryu-chan!
やばい、なんか幼馴染面で近づいてきたのと思って、
Oh man, I thought 'She's approaching me with a childhood friend face',
すごいドキドキしてます。
and my heart is pounding.
本当、可愛くぶっちゃった。
I really acted cute.
可愛い！これポーズ可愛い、これ。
Cute! This pose is so cute.
可愛いでしょ？
Cute, right?
可愛い。
Cute.
龍ちゃん、見て見て！
Ryu-chan, look, look!
可愛い！
Cute!
言っちゃった。
I said it.
ねぇみんな、僕の分も褒めてあげてください。
Hey everyone, please praise my part too.
僕はあまり褒めないので。
Since I don't praise myself much.
褒めろよ！
Praise me!
可愛い、本当に可愛い。
Cute, really cute.
おい龍ちゃん、あざといポーズしろ！
Hey Ryu-chan, do a cunning pose!
一緒にしよう。
Let's do it together.
可愛い！キュンキュンキュン。
Cute! Heart-throbbing heart!
最高やないの。
Isn't it the best?
いいじゃないの。
Isn't it good?
え、なんかポーズしようよ。
Eh, let's do some pose.
希望あればなんなりと。
Whatever your requests may be.
パンチ！
Punch!
パンチ。いいでもね、クソ雑魚パンチしたもんね、我々一緒に。
Punch. But we did a weakling punch together, didn't we?
超強パンチ！
Super strong punch!
超強パンチ？
Super strong punch?
かかってこいや。
Come at me!
最高。強そう。
Great. Looks strong.
強そう。本当に強そうになっちゃった。
Looks strong. It really turned out looking strong.
撃退したいリプライとかあったらね、これ使ってもらって。
If you have replies you want to repel, please use this.
使ってこなそう。かかって今回。
Probably won't use it. Come at us this time.
我々が倒します。かかってこい、かかってこい。
We will defeat them. Come at us, come at us.
クソリプ。
Shitty replies.
クソリプ、全て倒します。見て、龍ちゃん好きそう。
Shitty replies, we'll defeat them all. Look, Ryu-chan seems to like it.
可愛い、マジで可愛い。
Cute, seriously cute.
好きそう。素敵。
Seems to like it. Wonderful.
いい。ちょっとポーズはさておき素敵よ。
Nice. Poses aside, it's wonderful.
やった！ポーズも褒めて！
Yay! Praise the pose too!
うん、この適当なポーズも褒めて。めちゃくちゃいい感じでしょ？
Yeah, praise this random pose too. It's a really good feeling, right?
強そう。おー、いくつか可愛い。
Looks strong. Oh, several cutes.
止まんないよもう、褒め出したら。
I won't stop anymore once I start praising.
やばい、やばい、やばい、やばい。
Oh no, oh no, oh no.
本当に嬉しいでございます。
I'm truly happy.
今日呼んでよかった。
I'm glad I invited you today.
マジ呼んでくれてありがとう。
Seriously, thanks for inviting me.
ありがた、ありがた。
Thank you, thank you.
今日はね、まだ……
Today, still...
締めるの下手かもと思って。
I thought maybe I'm bad at closing.
頑張ってね。バイバイ！
Good luck. Bye bye!
ねぇ、おつばくー！
Hey, Happy Birthday stream!
あいつマジで本当に雑なんだよ。
That person is seriously just so careless.
はい、というわけで翠でした。
Alright, so that was Midori.
龍ちゃんでもなんでも呼んであげてください。
Please call him Ryu-chan or whatever.
じゃあロボ子も次頑張りますので。
Well, Roboco will do her best next too.
うーー、パンチ！
Ooh... PUNCH!
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡と消えそうなshy love
Shy love about to vanish like a bubble
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡のはじけるチャイナ
China bursting like a bubble
ロボ子ちゃん誕生日おめでとう！
Roboco-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thanks!
春茶ん、バーチャルの世界へようこそ！
Haru-chan, welcome to the virtual world!
頭の中真っ黒になっちゃっぽ
My head has become pitch black
頭真っ黒？ロボ子も……
Head pitch black? Roboco too...
……うまいこと、うまいこと。行ってきます！
...nicely, nicely. Here I go!
wow wow wow 我愛尓 きみに我愛尓
Wow wow wow, Wo ai ni, Wo ai ni to you
我愛尓 我愛尓 あなたに
Wo ai ni, Wo ai ni to you
いとも簡単に陥る
Falling for you so easily
我愛尓 我愛尓 我愛尓
Wo ai ni, Wo ai ni, Wo ai ni
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡と消えそうなshy love
Shy love about to vanish like a bubble
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡のはじけるチャイナ
China bursting like a bubble
戦場のモンアミ きみに
Mon ami of the battlefield, to you
我愛尓 我愛尓 我愛尓 そこに
Wo ai ni, Wo ai ni, Wo ai ni, there
昼夜の公海に 終わる
Ending in the high seas of day and night
我愛尓 我愛尓 我愛尓
Wo ai ni, Wo ai ni, Wo ai ni
ねぇ そろそろ やめちゃいな
Hey, why don't you stop already
チャイナチャイナチャイナ
China China China
チャイナ・アドバイス
China Advice
もう 私の虜にね
Already a captive of mine
チャイナチャイナチャイナ
China China China
チャイナ・アドバイス
China Advice
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡と消えそうなshy love
Shy love about to vanish like a bubble
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡のはじけるチャイナ
China bursting like a bubble
徐々に限界に 潜む
Gradually lurking at the limit
我愛尓 我愛尓 我愛尓
Wo ai ni, Wo ai ni, Wo ai ni
そっと 曖昧に
Gently, vaguely
大胆な限界に 挑む
Challenging the bold limit
我愛尓 我愛尓 我愛尓
Wo ai ni, Wo ai ni, Wo ai ni
ねぇ そろそろ やめちゃいな
Hey, why don't you stop already
チャイナチャイナチャイナ
China China China
チャイナ・アドバイス
China Advice
いい加減に大人になっちゃいなよ
Just grow up and be an adult already
チャイナチャイナチャイナ
China China China
チャイナ・アドバイス
China Advice
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡と消えそうなshy love
Shy love about to vanish like a bubble
I wanna do it do it yeah
泡のはじけるチャイナ
China bursting like a bubble
ねぇ そろそろ やめちゃいな
Hey, why don't you stop already
チャイナチャイナチャイナ
China China China
チャイナ・アドバイス
China Advice
チャイナアドバイス
もう私のとりこになって
Become my captive already
チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナアドバイス
China, China, China, China advice
さあ、受けとめてその手にどうぞ
Come on, catch it in your hands, please
チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナアドバイス
China, China, China, China advice
あぁ、私ものめりこんで
Ah, I'm falling for you too
チャイナ チャイナ チャイナ チャイナアドバイス
China, China, China, China advice
はるちゃーん！
Haru-chan!
嬉しい、一緒に歌えて！
I'm so happy to sing with you!
楽しかった！
It was fun!
楽しかった！ありがとう！
It was fun! Thank you!
こちらこそありがとう！
Thank you too!
はるちゃんそこから出るんだね、今日
Haru-chan, you're coming out of there today?
そう、そう。ここがお家
Yeah, yeah. Today this is my home.
すごいよねこれね
This is amazing, isn't it?
え、すごいよね
Yeah, it's amazing.
というわけで、今日ははるちゃんがゲストに来てくれました！
So, today we have Haru-chan as our guest!
こんにちは、はるです
Hello, I'm Haru.
やっほ、はるです
Hi, I'm Haru.
はるちゃんがさ、すごい多分みんなも
Haru-chan, I think everyone's like...
「え、そこ接点あるの？」って、すごい思われてると思うよね
"Wait, you two have a connection?" I bet they think that.
一回だけね、ポストとかでね
Just once, I posted about it.
した
Did.
そう、お土産
Yeah, a souvenir.
そう、お土産をあげたの
Yeah, I gave a souvenir.
もらった
I received it.
で、実ははるちゃんからも僕はお土産をもらってる
And actually, I received a souvenir from Haru-chan too.
確かにあげたわ
I did give you one.
そう、でもそれはポストしてない
But I haven't posted about that.
なんだかんだ、結構遊んでたりもしたからね
We've been hanging out quite a bit after all.
今回はお呼びしました
So I invited her this time.
どうでしたか？
How was it?
え、私に聞いてる、今？
Are you asking me?
え、みんなに聞いてる
I'm asking everyone.
あ、みんなね！
Oh, everyone!
え、でもどうだった、一緒に歌って？
But how was it singing together?
え、超楽しかった
It was so much fun.
嬉しい、僕も楽しかった
I'm happy, I had fun too.
ね、初めて歌ってさ、歌ったよね？
We sang together for the first time, right?
歌ったよ
We did.
そうだよね？
Right?
歌った
We did.
こういう場所でね
In a place like this.
ね、そうだよね
Right.
だってさ、声色が結構さ、近いからさ
Because our voices are quite similar...
あ、絶対これ似合うやと思って
I thought this would definitely suit us.
今回はチャイナアドバイス、選びました
So I chose "China Advice" this time.
ロボ子が決めたの？
Roboco decided?
うん
Yeah.
あ、そうなんだ
Oh, I see.
え、個性的でしょ？
It's unique, right?
すごい
Amazing.
個性
Unique.
さすが
As expected.
はるちゃんがさ、珍しいんだよ
Haru-chan is rare.
僕のこと「ロボ子」って呼ぶの
She calls me "Roboco".
え、そうなの？
Oh, is that so?
そう、珍しいんだよね
Yeah, it's rare.
あまりいないの、マジで
Not many people do, seriously.
さっき聞いた、びっくりした
I just heard that, it surprised me.
もうナチュラルにずっと「ロボ子」なの
It's just naturally "Roboco" all the time.
そう、ずっとロボ子
Yeah, always Roboco.
え、逆に何？何が多い？
Conversely, what do others call you?
えー、ロボちゃんとか、ロボ...
Robo-chan, Robo...
先輩とか
Senpai...
あ、ね、それちょっとよくわかんない
I don't really get that.
先輩なの、ロボ子？
Are you a senpai, Roboco?
え、そう、先輩なんですよ、一応
Yeah, technically I am a senpai.
えー？
Eh?
え、ねぇねぇ、なんかこれ、本当やりたかったけど、できな... 忘れてた
Hey, I really wanted to do this, but I couldn't... I forgot.
ハート作ります
I'll make a heart.
ハート
Heart.
え、そこ、あ、いけそうじゃない？
Oh, looks like we can do it!
みんな、みんな写真撮って！
Everyone, take a picture!
みんな写真撮って！
でも、いい感じや
It looks good, though.
え、可愛い
It's cute.
え、どう、これ？新しい衣装なんですけれど
So, how's this? My new outfit.
超可愛いと思います
I think it's super cute.
え、はるちゃん的におすすめのポーズとかあったら撮っちゃうんだけど
If you have any recommended poses, Haru-chan, I'll do them.
え、ちょっと、あれやってよ。上目遣い
Try that one. Looking up from below.
上目遣い？
Looking up?
え、カメラ... カメラ...
The camera... camera...
可愛い、可愛い！
Cute, cute!
はるちゃん！
Haru-chan!
いっぱい遊んで！
Play with me a lot!
可愛い！
Cute!
いっぱい遊ぼう！
Let's play a lot!
でも、手はごついんだね
But your hands are chunky.
ね、そう、めちゃめちゃかっこいい。見て！
Yeah, it's super cool. Look!
え、でも好きでしょ、こういうの？
You like this kind of stuff, right?
ごつい
Chunky.
かっこいい
Cool.
これ、めっちゃ高い
This was really expensive.
高いんだ
Expensive, huh?
おー、めちゃめちゃ高い
Wow, super expensive.
多分、パパが作ってくれた
Probably. My papa made it for me.
パパもすごいの
Your papa is amazing too.
うん、パパもすごいな
Yeah, papa is amazing.
え、お団子もさ、超可愛くない？
Aren't the hair buns super cute too?
え、お団子可愛いでしょう？見て！
The buns are cute, right? Look!
そう、毛量がめちゃめちゃあるんです、ロボ子
Roboco has a lot of hair.
後ろから見るとすごいね
Looking from the back, it's amazing.
ボボボボボボボ！
Bo-bo-bo-bo-bo-bo!
全部可愛い
Everything is cute.
やったー！オールパーフェクトじゃん
Yay! It's all perfect then.
はるちゃんこれ途中でやってたの気づいた？
Haru-chan, did you notice I was doing this in the middle?
これ？歌中？
This? During the song?
やってた
I was doing it.
気づいてた、気づいてた
I noticed, I noticed.
なんか、こっち見てやってたよね、しかも
You were looking over here while doing it, too.
「気づけー」って、ドヤ顔でやってた
"Notice me!" I was doing it with a smug look.
気づいた、気づいた
I noticed, I noticed.
というわけで
Anyway...
本当におめでとう
Congratulations, really.
ロボ子... なんか...
Roboco... well...
本当に、おめでとうって
Truly, congratulations.
すごい、めちゃめちゃ丁寧に言ってくれるからさ
You're saying it so politely.
おめでたいんだもんだって
Because it's a happy occasion.
え、嬉しい、ありがとう
I'm happy, thank you.
次も
Next time, too.
まだ早いか
Is it still early?
いいよ
Sure.
大丈夫か
Is it okay?
え、まだね、いっぱいあると思うからね、頑張るね
I think there's still a lot to come, so I'll do my best.
頑張って
Do your best.
はるちゃん、応援してね
Support me, Haru-chan.
応援する、見てるね
I'll support you. I'm watching.
見てて。ありがとう
Please watch. Thank you.
バイバイ！
Bye bye!
バイバイ、はるちゃーん！
Bye bye, Haru-chan!
バイバイ！
Bye bye!
またね！
See you!
おめでとう、バイバイ！
Congratulations, bye bye!
はるちゃんって、結構マイペースなんですよ
Haru-chan is quite "my pace".
どいつもこいつもなんだかやっぱノーテンキ
Everyone around seems so carefree,
気になるあの娘も悩みはきっとあるでしょ？
But still, that girl I’m interested in has her own troubles, right?
ざっくり半端な憂鬱ともあふれ同じ
A bunch of miscellaneous and depressed melancholy people
頭の中はぐちゃぐちゃさ
My head is all jumbled up
どんまい平気だい 意気地がないの放っておいてイージー
Don't worry, it's fine, leave my spinelessness alone, it's easy
いけないいけない事柄なんてないから
Because there's no such thing as things you shouldn't do
嫌刺す じゃんけんぽんで さあおゆき
Hateful stabs, rock-paper-scissors, now go forth
うじうじ爆弾で 産み出されてく
Born from a hesitating bomb
君はもうハイスピードだな
You're already at high speed
お前も同感 おあつらえ
You agree too, it's just right
はっちゃけ めっちゃくなドラマ
A wild and crazy drama
ドラが鳴るよ
The gong rings
い・い・許婚っきゅん I Love You なのだ
I-I-Fiancé-Kyun, I love you, that's what it is
四六時中 愛をちょうだい
I want love all the time
い・い・い・いちかばちきゅん
I-I-I-Take-a-chance-Kyun
愛、愛、愛は無敵 二分の一じゃ物足りない
Love, love, love is invincible, 1/2 isn't enough
それでも結局見えないあいつの胸の内
But in the end, I still can't see into his heart
惜しまれさだめ 浮気通りもいらないから
I don't need a regretted fate or infidelity
先輩後輩ヤンキーちゃんきー関係ない
Seniors, juniors, punks, it doesn't matter
いざ尋常に勝負
Now, let's have a fair fight
君がもしも その気なら
If you're up for it
ボイミーツガールが始まりそうならさあ
If it looks like a boy-meets-girl is about to start, then go
まだ見ぬ技 繰り出す
Unleashing a technique not yet seen
僕ら 手強い スイートだな
We're tough and sweet
お前も同感 おあつらえ
You agree too, it's just right
へっちゃら呉れない 修羅場
A scene that doesn't care
ドラが鳴るよ
The gong rings
意味深な内容 あいまいな愛より直行
Suggestive content, straight to it rather than vague love
四の五の言わず さしてちょうだい
Stop complaining and just point it out
待って！ 1ピコまで全集中 話望まず
Wait! Concentrate fully down to 1 pico, don't want to talk
自分の意思はどんなもんじゃい
What's your own will like?
い・い・許婚っきゅん I Love You なのだ
I-I-Fiancé-Kyun, I love you, that's what it is
四六時中 愛をちょうだい
I want love all the time
い・い・いちかばちきゅん 愛、愛、愛は無敵
I-I-Take-a-chance-Kyun, love, love, love is invincible
二分の一じゃ物足りない
1/2 isn't enough
こんなんじゃ知らない 会いたいかも知れない
I don't know if it's like this, I might want to see you
毎晩期待 1000回じゃ足りないや
Expecting every night, 1000 times isn't enough
偶然絶後 兵士占う
Unprecedented coincidence, soldier fortune-telling
変愛無常 めっちゃ回転
Weird love, inconstant, rotating like crazy
はい、というわけで、許婚っきゅんでしたー！どうでしたかー？
Alright, so that was 'Iinazukkyun'! How was it?
え、シルエットのさ、ここかっこよくなかった？
Hey, wasn't this silhouette part cool?
ボン、ボンってしてんの
Going boom, boom like that.
結構お気に入りポイントです
It's one of my favorite parts.
はい、どうだった？
So, how did you like it?
可愛いでしょ、改めて新衣装
Isn't the new outfit cute?
ねー、ミドりともポルちゃんともね、歌えて嬉しい
Yeah, I'm happy I could sing with Midori and Polka-chan.
まさかの「えー」って思ってる人がね、めっちゃ多かったと思うんだけど
I think many people were like "What?!", but...
お呼びしました、今回は
I invited them this time.
嬉しいです
I'm so happy.
さあ、というわけで
Now then...
結構歌ったね
I've sung quite a lot.
なんかそろそろウズウズしてる人たちがいっぱいいる気がするなー
I feel like there are a lot of people getting restless soon.
ウズ、ウズ、ウズ、ウズ、ウズ...
Restless, restless, restless...
僕が一番ウズウズしてる
I'm the one who's most restless.
はい、というわけで、待てができないので、ご紹介したいと思います
So, since I can't wait anymore, I'd like to introduce...
誕生日といえば...
Speaking of birthdays...
誕生日グッズ！
Birthday Merchandise!
今回の誕生日グッズはこちら！
Here is this time's birthday merchandise!
はい、久々にタペストリーを出します
Yes, I'm releasing a tapestry after a long time.
まず一つ目、B2タペストリー！
First one, B2 Tapestry!
こちらイラストはね、とってもクールな僕なんですけれども
This illustration is a very cool version of me,
しゃがむ先生に描いていただきました
drawn by Syagamu-sensei.
え、あ、これ「龍」違いとかやめてね
Hey, don't confuse the 'Dragon' or anything.
龍！お前も好きだし
Dragon! I like you too,
お前も好きだぞ、みんな愛してる、龍です
and you too. I love you all. It's a Dragon.
めっちゃかっこいいよね
It's really cool, isn't it?
強そうな龍と強そうな僕、かっこいいでしょ
A strong-looking dragon and a strong-looking me. Cool, right?
そして二つ目は...
And the second one is...
なんとお腹いっぱい食べちゃう餃子皿！
A 'eat your fill' dumpling plate!
なんとこちらロボ子先生が書いてくれました
Actually, Roboco-sensei drew this!
見て、なんかすごいいい...
Look, it's really good...
おなかいっぱいになっちゃうね！お皿に、はまってるロボ子とロボサ
The 'I'm getting full!' plate, featuring Roboco and Robosa being obsessed with it,
めちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょ？
is super cute, isn't it?
このお皿使っていっぱいね、餃子なりなんなり食べてください！
Please use this plate to eat lots of gyoza or whatever you like!
おなかいっぱいになると幸せになるのでね！
Because getting full makes you happy!
はい！そして次は…
Alright! And next is...
ご飯を食べたら喉も渇く！『ちぁーず！グラス』ですね！
After eating, you get thirsty! It's the 'Cheers!' glass!
ビール入れてもいいし、お茶入れたっていいし、ジュース入れたっていい！
You can put beer, tea, or even juice in it!
おいしいもの飲んでいきましょう！
Let's drink something delicious!
こちらもなんと、ロボ子先生が書いてくれました！
Believe it or not, Roboco-sensei drew this one too!
高性能だなぁ…可愛すぎる！
Such high performance... it's too cute!
こんなウィンクされたらいっぱい飲んだってね、いいですからね！
With a wink like that, it's okay to drink a lot!
ふふ！ぜひご飯と飲み物、
Hehe! Please use them for your food and drinks
食卓にお使いくださいませ！僕も今度配信で使ってみようと思うので、
at your dining table! I'm planning to use them in a stream soon,
ぜひチェックしてみてください！そしてまだまだあります！こちらドン！
so please check it out! And there's still more! Here we go!
はい！僕の大好きなぬいぐるみ！
Yes! My favorite, a plushie!
本日も可愛いものができました！見て！
We made another cute one today! Look!
おすわりしてるの！今回の『おすわりぬいぐるみ』！
It's sitting! This time it's a 'Sitting Plushie'!
ちゃんとロボサもね、ここにいますよ！
And Robosa is right here too!
今回のおすわりぬいぐるみなので、
Since it's a sitting plushie this time,
そのままお部屋に飾ってもいいし、お出かけにも一緒に写真撮りやすいのかなと思います！
you can display it in your room as is, or take it out for photos easily!
はい！いっぱい色んなところに連れて行ってあげてください！
Yes! Please take it with you to lots of different places!
大切にしてね！無くさないでね！置いていかないでね！
Take good care of it! Don't lose it! Don't leave it behind!
たくさん買ったって、いいんだからね！ふふ！
It's okay to buy a lot of them! Hehe!
そしてボイスも出ます！
And voice packs are coming out too!
今回は、シチュエーションボイス『ぼく vs りゅう』！
This time, the situation voice is 'Me vs Dragon'!
マジ龍の名前、さだまらんのよね。緑だったり、龍だったり、
Seriously, I can't settle on the dragon's name. Midori, Ryu,
ドラゴンくんだったり、ドラちゃんだったり…何だっていい！ふふ！
Dragon-kun, Dra-chan... anything works! Hehe!
君に襲いかかる龍に可愛さ勝負を挑む、僕のお話！
It's a story of me challenging the dragon attacking you to a cuteness contest!
きゅん！
Kyun!
はい！どんなお話かはぜひ買って聞いてみてください！
Yes! Please buy it and listen to find out what kind of story it is!
さぁ、最後にこちら！
Now, finally, this!
はい！今回のフルセット購入特典についてお話しします！
Yes! I'll talk about the full set purchase bonus!
まず一つ目！数量限定版が今回はあります！
First of all! We have a limited quantity edition this time!
数量限定版は僕の直筆サインと、
The limited edition comes with my handwritten signature,
箔押しの複製メッセージ入りのポストカードになります！
and a postcard with a foil-stamped printed message!
はい！ぜひ！
Yes! Please get it!
今回は僕のこの配信が終わったと同時にカートがオープンしますので、
The cart will open as soon as this stream ends,
そのタイミングでぜひ狙ってみてください！
so please try to grab it at that moment!
スタートダッシュの準備はいいかー！
Are you ready for the start dash?!
ぜひゲットしてくださいね！
Please make sure to get it!
はい、もちろん通常版もあります！
Yes, of course, there's a standard edition too!
通常版は僕の直筆サインはないんですけど、箔押し入りのサインと、
The standard edition doesn't have a handwritten signature, but it has a foil-stamped one,
メッセージのポストカードがついてきますので、ぜひゲットしてください！
and the message postcard is included, so please get it!
そして、まだフルセット購入特典にはボイスがつきます！
And there's more! The full set purchase bonus also includes a voice pack!
一つ目、『きみと龍と夜の空』！
First, 'You, the Dragon, and the Night Sky'!
こちらは販売ボイスの、少しあとの時間帯のお話で、
This is a story set a little after the main voice pack,
なんと時間軸は続いております！
and believe it or not, the timeline continues!
ふん！販売ボイスは別に単体でも楽しめますけど、
Hmph! You can enjoy the main voice pack on its own,
特典ボイスも合わせると『えっ、あのあとの続きがあるの？』って楽しめるので、
but with the bonus pack, you'll be like 'Wait, there's a sequel?!' so it's fun,
ぜひ聞いてほしいです！面白いよ！
I really want you to listen to it! It's interesting!
そしてなんと今回は…ジャーン！
And believe it or not, this time... Ta-da!
タレントプレミアムグッズのフルセット特典として、
As a full set bonus for the talent premium goods,
2024年から9月から発売がされた、ホロライブ・オフィシャル・カードゲームで
from the Hololive Official Card Game released in September 2024,
使用できるカードが1枚ついてきます！
you get one card you can use!
同梱するカードは、ホロライブプロダクション・オフィシャルショップで購入されたお客様のみの対象となります！
The included card is only for customers who purchase from the Hololive Production Official Shop!
今回特典につくのは、ゲームで1枚だけ使用でき、
The one included as a bonus can be used once in the game,
推しをアピールすることができるカード、『推しホロメンカード』です！
and it's an 'Oshi Holomen Card' that lets you show off your favorite!
え、みんな欲しいっしょこれ？1枚、今しか買えない！
Hey, everyone wants this, right? It's a one-off, only available now!
ロボサは買うべき！強いよ！
Robosa should buy it! It's strong!
はい、というわけで、カードの詳細や遊び方については、
Alright, so for details on the card and how to play,
多分僕から聞くより、ホロライブ・オフィシャル・カードゲームの公式ホームページで、
rather than hearing it from me, checking the Hololive Official Card Game official website
確認した方が分かりやすいと思うので、ぜひチェックしてみてください！
will be easier to understand, so please go check it out!
はい、同梱するカードは日本版のみとなりますのでご了承ください！
Yes, please note that the included card is Japanese version only!
ノー・イングリッシュ・ソーリー！
No English, sorry!
グッズのカートオープンはこのあと配信終了後になりますので、
The goods cart will open right after this stream ends,
みんな待機して買ってね！
so everyone, please wait and buy them!
いっぱい買ったっていいんだからね！
It's okay to buy a lot, you know!
そして、
And then,
この後はなんと
what comes next is,
実は初めての
actually, for the first time...
メインえ、アル、アル... アルコールライブがあります！
the main ev... al... al... alcohol live!
酒は飲んでも飲まれるな！
Don't let the alcohol drink you!
最近お酒飲んでない
I haven't been drinking lately.
アンコールとアルコール、似てるんだわ
'Encore' and 'Alcohol' sound similar.
はい。というわけで、なんと今回はね
Yes. So, surprisingly this time...
アンコールライブがありますので
...there's an encore live!
みんながずっと僕に歌ってほしそうだった、あの曲を歌っちゃおうかなと思ってます
I'm going to sing that song that everyone has been wanting me to sing.
楽しみにしててくださーい！
Please look forward to it!
せっかくですからね、写真撮影会とかね
Since we're here, maybe a photo session or...
ロボさーと密な空間でいっぱい見せちゃおうかなって思ってます
...showing you plenty in a close-knit space with the Robosa.
メンバーのプレゼントもありがとね！みんなぜひ見ててください！
Thanks for the membership gifts too! Everyone, please watch!
はい、というわけで、ロボさー
Yes. So, Robosa...
早いけど、次が最後の曲になっちゃうみたいです
it's early, but it looks like the next one will be the last song.
僕はもう、９歳
I'm already 9 years old.
９歳になってるロボさー、ここまで成長を見届けてくれてありがとね
Robosa, thank you for watching me grow to be 9 years old.
これからもまだまだ僕は成長していくので、一緒に末長く楽しんでいきましょう！
I'll keep growing, so let's enjoy our time together for a long time!
最後の曲は、初めにちらっと言ったけど
The last song, as I mentioned briefly at the start...
ドラゴンくんに乗りたいな！
...is I want to ride Dragon-kun!
一緒に頑張ってくれる？ね、ドラゴンくん？
Will you do your best with me? Right, Dragon-kun?
DAN DAN 心魅かれてく
Bit by bit, my heart is charmed by you
その眩しい笑顔に
By that dazzling smile
果てない暗闇から飛び出そう
Let's fly out of the endless darkness
Hold my hand
君と出会ったとき
When I met you,
子供のころ大切に思っていた
I remembered the scenery
景色を思い出したんだ
I cherished in my childhood.
僕と踊ってくれないか
Won't you dance with me?
光と影の Winding Road
On the winding road of light and shadow,
今でも あいつに夢中なの？
are you still crazy about him?
少しずつ 振り向いて
Turn around little by little,
確かめたくなるような 時もあるけど
even though there are times I want to make sure.
愛と勇気と誇りを持って 闘うよ
I'll fight with love, courage, and pride.
DAN DAN 心魅かれてく
Bit by bit, my heart is charmed by you,
この星の希望の欠片
pieces of hope of this star.
きっと誰もが 永遠を手にいれたい
Surely everyone wants to obtain eternity.
ぜんぜん 気にしないフリしても
Even if I pretend not to care at all,
ほら 君に恋してる
look, I'm in love with you.
果てない暗闇から飛び出そう
Let's fly out of the endless darkness,
Hold my hand
怒った顔も疲れてる 君も好きだけど
I love you even when you're angry or look tired,
あんなに飛ばして生きて大丈夫かなと思う
but I wonder if you're okay, living at such a pace.
僕はなにげない仕草に 振り回されてる 潮風に
I'm tossed around by your casual gestures and the sea breeze.
それでも あいつに夢中なの？
Even so, are you still crazy about him?
もっと聞きたいことがあったのに
There was more I wanted to ask,
二人の会話が車の音に
but our conversation was drowned out
阻まれて通りに舞うよ
by the sound of cars, dancing on the street.
DAN DAN 心魅かれてく
Bit by bit, my heart is charmed by you.
自分でも不思議なんだけど
It's strange even to me,
何かあるとすぐに 君に電話したくなる
but whenever something happens, I want to call you.
全然気のないフリしても
Even if I pretend to have no interest at all...
結局 君のことだけ見ていた
In the end, I was only looking at you.
海の彼方へ
To the far side of the sea,
飛び出そうよ
let's jump out...
Hold my hand
おっとっとっと
Whoops!
みんなー！ ろぼさー！
Everyone! Robosars!
今日は見てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for watching today!
この後はなんと メンバー限定でも歌います！
After this, I'll even be singing in a members-only stream!
遊びに来てねー！
Come and visit!
グッズもめっちゃかわちいから ゲットしてくれよなー！
The merch is also super cute, so please get some!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
なんか君も遅いね、ドラゴンくん
You're kind of slow too, Dragon-kun.
はろ〜ぼ飯店 ようこそ
Welcome to Haroubo Restaurant
NEXT アンコールライブ
NEXT: Encore Live